<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Running Images - 2005-2009</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/2005-2009.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>A Glimpse of Heaven and A Taste of Hell</title><link href="/a-glimpse-of-heaven-and-a-taste-of-hell.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tyler Bourns</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/a-glimpse-of-heaven-and-a-taste-of-hell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Here you will get a chance to see what the 400 entrants from around the world experienced when competing in an ultra distance endurance run on the...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here you will get a chance to see what the 400 entrants from around the world experienced when competing in an ultra distance endurance run on the world famous Tahoe Rim Trail. Athletes were able to choose from a 50K, 50 miler, or the exhausting 100-Mile National Championship Event. Hosted by Kelly Quinn and told by the participants and volunteers you will discover both the story of ultra running as well as the colorful history of this event.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category></entry><entry><title>Indulgence: 1000 Miles Under the Colorado Sky</title><link href="/indulgence-1000.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alex Nichols</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/indulgence-1000.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The film details his training for that year’s Leadville 100 and his philosophy on ultrarunning in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The film details his training for that year’s Leadville 100 and his philosophy on ultrarunning in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Leadville 100"></category><category term="Anton Krupicka"></category></entry><entry><title>La marche intérieure</title><link href="/la-marche-interieure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Didier Lafond</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/la-marche-interieure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Short tv documentary on the 2008 edition of UTMB, the first edition won by a 21 year old Kilian Jornet. This films also shows the adventure of all...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short tv documentary on the 2008 edition of UTMB, the first edition won by a 21 year old Kilian Jornet. This films also shows the adventure of all the middle and back of the pack runnings, that spend two nights on the Mont Blanc.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="UTMB"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category></entry><entry><title>Run for your life</title><link href="/run-for-your-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Judd Ehrilich</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/run-for-your-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Without one eccentric, first-generation Jewish immigrant from Transylvania, the New York City Marathon simply wouldn't exist. Ehrlich's fun, loving...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Without one eccentric, first-generation Jewish immigrant from Transylvania, the New York City Marathon simply wouldn't exist. Ehrlich's fun, loving and inspirational tribute to the late Fred Lebow shows how one man's imagination, determination and love for running created one of the world's most popular sporting events.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Fred Lebow"></category></entry><entry><title>Running America</title><link href="/running-america.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Kerwin</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-america.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Charlie Engle (from Running the Sahara) and Ultra-Marathoner Marshall Ulrich press the human physical and mental strengths to their limits in a run...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charlie Engle (from Running the Sahara) and Ultra-Marathoner Marshall Ulrich press the human physical and mental strengths to their limits in a run from San Francisco to Times Square.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="US Transcontinental"></category><category term="Charlie Engle"></category></entry><entry><title>Running the Sahara</title><link href="/running-the-sahara.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>James Moll</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-the-sahara.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;This inspirational film chronicles three ultra marathoners' attempt to run the entire length of Africa's Sahara Desert.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This inspirational film chronicles three ultra marathoners' attempt to run the entire length of Africa's Sahara Desert.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Charlie Engle"></category></entry><entry><title>Spirit of the Marathon</title><link href="/spirit-of-the-marathon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Dunham</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/spirit-of-the-marathon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[wikipedia] Spirit of the Marathon is a 2007 documentary film directed by Jon Dunham. The film chronicles the journey six marathon runners...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[wikipedia] Spirit of the Marathon is a 2007 documentary film directed by Jon Dunham. The film chronicles the journey six marathon runners experience while training and competing in the 2005 Chicago Marathon. It was screened at the Chicago International Film Festival on October 5, 2007 and received a limited release in the United States on January 24, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Jon Dunham"></category></entry><entry><title>Terry Fox Remembered</title><link href="/terry-fox-remembered.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jim Eidt</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/terry-fox-remembered.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Beyond the funds raised for cancer research, Terry Fox and his Marathon of Hope left another, less visible legacy: a profound impact on the lives...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beyond the funds raised for cancer research, Terry Fox and his Marathon of Hope left another, less visible legacy: a profound impact on the lives of the thousands who crossed paths with the courageous young runner. These people remember Terry, not from television or newspaper reports, but from personal experience. For most, it was an unforgettable meeting. For many, it was an encounter that changed their lives forever. Terry Fox Remembered is their story.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Terry Fox"></category></entry><entry><title>The Runner: David Horton's 2700 Mile Run of the Pacific Crest Trail</title><link href="/the-runner.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>JB Benna</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-runner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;June 2005 - The Runner follows Extreme UltraRunner David Horton through the desert sun, the high snowbound mountain passes, the pain, the emotion,...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;June 2005 - The Runner follows Extreme UltraRunner David Horton through the desert sun, the high snowbound mountain passes, the pain, the emotion, and his revelation. Join him as he runs more than 40 miles per day for 66 consecutive days in an attempt to set the speed record on the 2,700 mile Pacific Crest Trail from Mexico to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="David Horton"></category><category term="JourneyFilm"></category><category term="JB Benna"></category></entry><entry><title>UltraMarathon Man: 50 Marathons • 50 States • 50 Days</title><link href="/ultra-marathon-man.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>JB Benna</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/ultra-marathon-man.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The inspirational film, UltraMarathon Man: 50 Marathons • 50 States • 50 Days, features renowned endurance athlete and best selling author Dean...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The inspirational film, UltraMarathon Man: 50 Marathons • 50 States • 50 Days, features renowned endurance athlete and best selling author Dean Karnazes in his attempt to run 50 marathons in 50 states in 50 consecutive days to raise awareness for youth obesity and to get America active. A beautiful and epic journey across the United States, during which Dean pushes the limits of human endurance, inspiring thousands across the country to join him along the path while uniting people of all ages and abilities to take “the next step.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="JourneyFilm"></category><category term="JB Benna"></category></entry><entry><title>Ultra-trail du Mont Blanc 2008</title><link href="/ultra-trail-du-mont-blanc-2008.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Denis Lafont</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/ultra-trail-du-mont-blanc-2008.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Reportage sympathique, qui met en valeur l'aventure plutôt que les élites, où l'arriveée de Kilian a lieu au millieu du film, et pas à la fin, car...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reportage sympathique, qui met en valeur l'aventure plutôt que les élites, où l'arriveée de Kilian a lieu au millieu du film, et pas à la fin, car pour tout les autres coureurs n'aventure n'est pas finie. 2008 est l'année où Kilian gagne l'UTMB pour la première fois et devient le plus jeune gagnant de l'histoire de la course.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="UTMB"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category></entry></feed>