<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Running Images - 2010-2014</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/2010-2014.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>52 peaks</title><link href="/52-peaks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Matthew Dickinson</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/52-peaks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;52 Peaks is a beautiful and contemplative film completely directed, produced, edited, animated, and starring Matthew Dickinson. It follows him as...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;52 Peaks is a beautiful and contemplative film completely directed, produced, edited, animated, and starring Matthew Dickinson.  It follows him as he attempts to run 52 peaks in 52 weeks all across New Zealand.  The personal journey that the film shows him going on throughout is motivational and his progress in running towards the end is evident.
The documentary is very introspective on running alone and tackling a challenge you set before yourself.  It is a great reminder that hard work and perseverance can pay off.  Shot with a single camera, Dickinson does a lot more running than required to bring us along.  But what an incredible journey we’re shown.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>An Endurance Life with Sébastien Chaigneau</title><link href="/an-endurance-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Étienne Valentin</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/an-endurance-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Sebastien Chaigneau is a runner; he runs distances of between 120 and 200 km across mountains. In this documentary he shows us his daily training...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sebastien Chaigneau is a runner; he runs distances of between 120 and 200 km across mountains. In this documentary he shows us his daily training routine amidst constant weather changes and we also witness more human aspects, such as his feelings and motivation during races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sébastien Chaigneau aime la montagne et prend son plaisir à courir des distances hors du commun, allant jusqu'à 160km. Entre joie et souffrance, il nous fait découvrir sa vie de coureur à travers ses entrainements et courses dans le monde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastien Chaigneau es un corredor de fondo, corre distancias de 120 a 200 kilómetros cruzando montañas. En el documental nos muestra su vida diaria de entrenamientos en medio de los cambios constantes del tiempo, así como la parte más humana, como son los sentimientos y la motivación en las carreras.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="Sébastien Chaigneau"></category><category term="Étienne Valentin"></category></entry><entry><title>Desert Runners</title><link href="/desert-runners.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jennifer Steinman</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/desert-runners.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[amazon] A diverse cast of non-professional runners attempt to complete the most difficult ultra-marathon race series on Earth. Their dramatic...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[amazon] A diverse cast of non-professional runners attempt to complete the most difficult ultra-marathon race series on Earth. Their dramatic journey takes them across the world's most picturesque yet brutal landscapes, pushing their bodies, hearts and spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Finding Traction</title><link href="/finding-traction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jaime Jacobsen</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/finding-traction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Ultra Runner Nikki Kimball takes on the 273-mile Long Trail. What drives someone to attempt such an incredible feat? Follow Nikki's journey from...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ultra Runner Nikki Kimball takes on the 273-mile Long Trail. What drives someone to attempt such an incredible feat? Follow Nikki's journey from its beginning to her actual record attempt through Vermont's beautiful but brutal Green Mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Hood to coast</title><link href="/hood-to-coast.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marcie Hume</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/hood-to-coast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[Runner's World] Runners who have ever wanted to participate in the Hood to Coast relay, one of the largest of its kind in the world, might want to...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[Runner's World] Runners who have ever wanted to participate in the Hood to Coast relay, one of the largest of its kind in the world, might want to take a peek at the 2011 documentary about this popular race in Oregon. The relay is approximately 200 miles long and features more than a thousand 12-person teams, and the film chronicles four groups who ran in the 2008 race. Grab 12 of your closest running buddies, watch the film, and sign up. But it’s a very popular race, so don’t hesitate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Into the wind</title><link href="/into-the-wind.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ezra Holland</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/into-the-wind.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[wikipedia] Into the Wind is a 2010 documentary film which chronicles the story of Terry Fox. At the age of 18, Fox was diagnosed with...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[wikipedia] Into the Wind is a 2010 documentary film which chronicles the story of Terry Fox. At the age of 18, Fox was diagnosed with osteosarcoma. The cancer had taken over his right leg, which was then amputated six inches above the knee. However, three years later, Fox set out to raise funds for cancer research and raise awareness by running 30 miles a day from the Atlantic Ocean in Newfoundland to the Pacific Ocean in British Columbia, totaling over 4000 miles.[1] The film was directed by the NBA star Steve Nash who grew up in Canada and followed Fox's run across the country as a kid in 1980, and narrated by Taylor Kitsch. Two thirds across Canada, Fox was once again diagnosed with cancer, which had spread to his lungs.[2] Fox died at the age of 22, inspiring the Terry Fox Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="Terry Fox"></category></entry><entry><title>Parti en diagonale (Grand Raid 2013)</title><link href="/parti-en-diagonale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alexis Berg</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/parti-en-diagonale.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;&amp;quot;La Diagonale des fous. Son nom dit tout ou presque. Cet ultra-trail tropical qui emprunte depuis plus de 20 ans le cadre unique et magique de...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;La Diagonale des fous. Son nom dit tout ou presque. Cet ultra-trail tropical qui emprunte depuis plus de 20 ans le cadre unique et magique de l'île de La Réunion a parcouru cette année, en 2013, près de 170 km et gravit 10 000 mètres de dénivelé positif. Elle a entraîné dans sa danse intense plus de 2000 « fous ». On l'a dit une des courses à pied les plus dures au monde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce défi sportif et humain revêt une signification différente pour chacun, un sens particulier pour chaque femme, chaque homme qui prend le départ. Pour moi, Frédéric, né le 1er septembre 1971 à Besançon, l'aventure c'est d'aller au bout, de vivre pleinement ce moment où les souffrances sont balayées par une magie qui confine à la poésie. Courir, marcher, souffrir, penser, divaguer, délirer... pour se sentir vivre. Maladivement. Follement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce film réalisé par mon frère Alexis est un témoignage. C'est le partage de deux frères qui se comprennent à la seconde sans trop se parler, c'est un regard posé par lui sur mon envie de transmettre par-dessus les mots. Transmettre ce modeste message  -- au bout de chaque tunnel il y a une lumière et putain qu'elle peut être belle cette lueur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merci à tous ceux qui m'ont aidé. Merci à lui et vive la folie quand elle court sur les plus beaux sentiers de la planète...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frédéric, dossard 1331.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="La Diagonale des Fous"></category><category term="Alexis Berg"></category></entry><entry><title>Profiling HURT</title><link href="/profiling-hurt.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Barry Walton</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/profiling-hurt.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Profiling HURT follows the path of ultra runner Mark Gilligan and his work to return to the race for a second year, to achieve what he couldn't in...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Profiling HURT follows the path of ultra runner Mark Gilligan and his work to return to the race for a second year, to achieve what he couldn't in his first. Joined by protagonist Scott Guild, the two take you to the course and drop you in the middle of it all so you can see what it's all about. Mud, injuries, training runs, and drop outs. It's not just a race for the finish, it's a battle to know how far you can go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>The Long Haul: John Muir Trail (Hal Koerner and Mike Wolfe)</title><link href="/the-long-haul.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>JB Benna</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-long-haul.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;JB Benna's short film recounts the story of Ultramarathoners Mike Wolfe and Hal Koerner as they set out to run the John Muir Trail in 2013 and best...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;JB Benna's short film recounts the story of Ultramarathoners Mike Wolfe and Hal Koerner as they set out to run the John Muir Trail in 2013 and best the previously record of 3 Days, 14 hours. The film features interviews with previous record holders and shares the history of this grueling feat. See the beauty, purity and ruggedness of the Sierra Nevada Mountains through their eyes as they struggle to complete this monumental and historic task.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="John Muir Trail"></category><category term="JourneyFilm"></category><category term="JB Benna"></category></entry><entry><title>Great Himalaya Trail, High Route – The Ultimate Trail</title><link href="/the-ultimate-trail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Anna Gatta</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-ultimate-trail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;In September 2013, Philippe and Anna Gatta left the small village of Simikot in the Western Nepal, aiming to run the high route of the Great...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In September 2013, Philippe and Anna Gatta left the small village of Simikot in the Western Nepal, aiming to run the high route of the Great Himalaya Trail in less than 40 days. Running the High Route in less than 40 days is the equivalent of 40 marathons in 40 days with 15 passes over 5,000 meters and two over 6,000m. This film tells their story.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>The worlds' highest running race - 222km</title><link href="/the-world-s-highest-race.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Wes Greene</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-world-s-highest-race.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Lisa Tamati takes you on a Himalayan adventure. The worlds' highest running race - known as La Ultra - The High is a 222km non stop running race...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lisa Tamati takes you on a Himalayan adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worlds' highest running race - known as La Ultra - The High is a 222km non stop running race over the two highest motorable mountain passes in the world.
Held in the Indian region of Ladakh (translated &amp;quot;The land of high passes&amp;quot;)  is a region in Indian state of Jammu and Kashmir that currently extends from the Kunlun mountain range  to the main Great Himalayas to the south, inhabited by people of Indo-Aryan and Tibetan descent.It is one of the most sparsely populated regions in Jammu and Kashmir and its culture and history are closely related to that of Tibet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past Ladakh gained importance from its strategic location at the crossroads of important trade routes, but since the Chinese authorities closed the borders with Tibet and Central Asia in the 1960s, international trade has dwindled but the Indian military maintains a strong hold there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year this incredibly tough ultra marathon is held. This is a documentary following Lisa Tamati racing it in its second year of running.
The first year only one man, Mark Cockbain, managed to finish and the other two competitors and some of the crew all ended up in hospital with altitude related problems
This race sees the competitors go  up twice within a very short time space to altitudes over 5,700m, climbing over the infamous Kardung La and Tanglang La passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxygen levels up there are around 30% of what they are at sea level making it extremely tough to get enough oxygen to run.
The terrain is mountainous, the rugged single lane roads frequented by military convoys spewing unfiltered diesel into the mountain air add to the difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competitors have extremes of temperature to deal with from 40 degrees celsius in the valleys to -3 in the mountains. This makes for slow going and there is more walking and running but don't underestimate how tough this is
Before Lisa even started she had a brain concussion to deal with a ripped ligaments on her left ankle ten weeks prior to going. Meaning she is undertrained and not well and during the race Lisa faces asthma attacks, heat exhaustion, severe altitude related problems, snow storms and treacherous roads to try and be the first woman to conquer this race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She ends up second behind the incredible Sharon Gayter from England but this 53hr and 5 minute odyssey will give the viewer a birdseye view on what its like to attempt something this mammoth, to face extreme fatigue, sleep deprivation and fear, altitude and health problems and to overcome and persevere against all odds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffer and celebrate with Lisa on this once in a life time journey&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Transcend</title><link href="/transcend.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tad Munnings</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/transcend.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Long-distance running allowed Wesley Korir to escape the grinding poverty of Kenya. But after winning multiple American marathons, including taking...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Long-distance running allowed Wesley Korir to escape the grinding poverty of Kenya. But after winning multiple American marathons, including taking running’s most cherished prize – the Boston Marathon, he risks it all and returns home to help his fellow Kenyans create better lives for themselves. In what proves to be the most challenging race of his career, Wesley takes on a well-financed, big-party candidate to run for a seat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in Kenyan parliament, attempting to balance the frenzy of campaigning with the demands of marathon training. Transcend is the story of the elusive spiritual energy that is somehow forged in the intense rigor of long-distance running, an energy Wesley Korir is using to transform the nation that has done more than any other to change the face of the marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Unbreakable</title><link href="/unbreakable.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>JB Benna</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/unbreakable.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Unbreakable: The Western States 100 follows the four lead men on this amazing journey. Hal Koerner, two time defending Western States champion, and...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unbreakable: The Western States 100 follows the four lead men on this amazing journey. Hal Koerner, two time defending Western States champion, and running store entrepreneur from Ashland, Oregon. Geoff Roes, undefeated at the 100-mile distance, an organic chef from Juneau, Alaska. Anton Krupicka, undefeated in every ultramarathon he has ever started, a graduate student living in Boulder, Colorado. Kilian Jornet, the young mountain runner and two time Ultra-trail du Mont-Blanc champion, from Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While their lives may be quite different, the goal is the same: win the Western States 100-mile run. A win will require breaking the course record and running the fastest time in the history of the race. An epic showdown ensues, from Squaw Valley, CA in Lake Tahoe, up though the high snow covered Sierra Nevada Mountains, down through the extreme heat of the American River Canyons and finishing in Auburn, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though all four are undefeated, three must break and only one can remain Unbreakable.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Anton Krupicka"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category><category term="JourneyFilm"></category><category term="JB Benna"></category></entry></feed>