<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Running Images</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>15 hours with Amelia Boone</title><link href="/15-hours-amelia-boone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/15-hours-amelia-boone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;&amp;quot;The Struggle Ends When the Gratitude Begins&amp;quot; | a quote Obstacle Course Racing Champion Amelia Boone leaned on when at the zenith of her endurance...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&amp;quot;The Struggle Ends When the Gratitude Begins&amp;quot;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;div class="first last line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;a quote Obstacle Course Racing Champion Amelia Boone leaned on when at the zenith of her endurance career in 2016, a stress fracture in her femur would sideline her for the next two years. Fast forward to February 3, 2018 as she toed the line of her first ultramarathon back at the Sean O'Brien 100K, Amelia reflects back on being injured and her newfound gratitude and perspective on running.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>15 hours with Ann Trason</title><link href="/15-hours-ann-trason.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/15-hours-ann-trason.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Arguably the greatest American ultrarunner of all time, Ann Trason won an unprecedented 14 times at the Western States 100 Mile Endurance Run while...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Arguably the greatest American ultrarunner of all time, Ann Trason won an unprecedented 14 times at the Western States 100 Mile Endurance Run while winning and setting course records at many other ultra races. But instead of embracing her incredible feats,  particularly in the 80-90's, a naturally introverted and modest Ann prefers to discuss the joy she feels on the trails and &amp;quot;competing with herself&amp;quot; versus those that toed the line with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this 3rd edition of &amp;quot;15 Hours&amp;quot; we follow the great Ann Trason on a day spent camping in the mountains of Bishop hiking in the High Sierras along with her dog. She opens up and shares her thoughts about her competitive years, why she shies away from the spotlight, her love of Western States and her thoughts on her portrayal in the best selling book &amp;quot;Born to Run&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Ann Trason"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>15 hours with Anton Krupicka</title><link href="/15-hours-anton-krupicka.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/15-hours-anton-krupicka.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;An intimate glimpse into a day in the life of famed and accomplished ultra runner Anton Krupicka as he shares his thoughts on his current injury,...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An intimate glimpse into a day in the life of famed and accomplished ultra runner Anton Krupicka as he shares his thoughts on his current injury, what it was like growing up in his hometown of Niobrara, Nebraska and his place in ultra running history.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Anton Krupicka"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>15 hours with Magdalena Boulet</title><link href="/15-hours-magdalena-boulet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/15-hours-magdalena-boulet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Magdalena Boulet wears many hats (yes, including her signature GU straw hat). In this latest snapshot of a typical day in the life of a remarkable...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Magdalena Boulet wears many hats (yes, including her signature GU straw hat). In this latest snapshot of a typical day in the life of a remarkable athlete, Magda opens up and shares what it was like to immigrate to the United States as a senior in high school, the virtues and values of hard work and the bittersweet day when she earned her American citizenship as the country was under attack on September 11th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch and listen to her fascinating journey into becoming one of the top ultramarathoners in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Magdalena Boulet"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>200, un film d’ultra</title><link href="/200-un-film-d-ultra.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Simon Dugué</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/200-un-film-d-ultra.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Yann Gobert, french ultra-runner, follows the GR30 to run 200km for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yann Gobert, french ultra-runner, follows the GR30 to run 200km for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>52 peaks</title><link href="/52-peaks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Matthew Dickinson</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/52-peaks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;52 Peaks is a beautiful and contemplative film completely directed, produced, edited, animated, and starring Matthew Dickinson. It follows him as...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;52 Peaks is a beautiful and contemplative film completely directed, produced, edited, animated, and starring Matthew Dickinson.  It follows him as he attempts to run 52 peaks in 52 weeks all across New Zealand.  The personal journey that the film shows him going on throughout is motivational and his progress in running towards the end is evident.
The documentary is very introspective on running alone and tackling a challenge you set before yourself.  It is a great reminder that hard work and perseverance can pay off.  Shot with a single camera, Dickinson does a lot more running than required to bring us along.  But what an incredible journey we’re shown.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>A Glimpse of Heaven and A Taste of Hell</title><link href="/a-glimpse-of-heaven-and-a-taste-of-hell.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tyler Bourns</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/a-glimpse-of-heaven-and-a-taste-of-hell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Here you will get a chance to see what the 400 entrants from around the world experienced when competing in an ultra distance endurance run on the...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here you will get a chance to see what the 400 entrants from around the world experienced when competing in an ultra distance endurance run on the world famous Tahoe Rim Trail. Athletes were able to choose from a 50K, 50 miler, or the exhausting 100-Mile National Championship Event. Hosted by Kelly Quinn and told by the participants and volunteers you will discover both the story of ultra running as well as the colorful history of this event.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category></entry><entry><title>A Long Day Out</title><link href="/a-long-day-out.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/a-long-day-out.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The greatest adventure might be hidden in your own backyard. Just outside your door you can put your shoes on and start running, and come back home...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The greatest adventure might be hidden in your own backyard. Just outside your door you can put your shoes on and start running, and come back home when you're tired. Join Kilian Jornet on a journey around the summits of his Norwegian home and be inspired to live your own adventure!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category><category term="Salomon"></category></entry><entry><title>A Race For The Soul</title><link href="/a-race-for-the-soul.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Brian Harder</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/a-race-for-the-soul.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Short film on the 2001 Western States. A very refreshing look into the middle/back-of-the-pack runners.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short film on the 2001 Western States. A very refreshing look into the middle/back-of-the-pack runners.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2000-2004"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Scott Jurek"></category><category term="Ann Trason"></category></entry><entry><title>An Endurance Life with Sébastien Chaigneau</title><link href="/an-endurance-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Étienne Valentin</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/an-endurance-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Sebastien Chaigneau is a runner; he runs distances of between 120 and 200 km across mountains. In this documentary he shows us his daily training...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sebastien Chaigneau is a runner; he runs distances of between 120 and 200 km across mountains. In this documentary he shows us his daily training routine amidst constant weather changes and we also witness more human aspects, such as his feelings and motivation during races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sébastien Chaigneau aime la montagne et prend son plaisir à courir des distances hors du commun, allant jusqu'à 160km. Entre joie et souffrance, il nous fait découvrir sa vie de coureur à travers ses entrainements et courses dans le monde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastien Chaigneau es un corredor de fondo, corre distancias de 120 a 200 kilómetros cruzando montañas. En el documental nos muestra su vida diaria de entrenamientos en medio de los cambios constantes del tiempo, así como la parte más humana, como son los sentimientos y la motivación en las carreras.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="Sébastien Chaigneau"></category><category term="Étienne Valentin"></category></entry><entry><title>Anton Kupricka, l’ovni de l’ultra trail</title><link href="/anton-krupicka-l-ovni-de-l-ultra-trail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Aurélien Delfosse</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/anton-krupicka-l-ovni-de-l-ultra-trail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;French TV short documentary on Anton Kupricka.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;French TV short documentary on Anton Kupricka.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="UTMB"></category><category term="Anton Krupicka"></category><category term="L´Equipe"></category><category term="Aurélien Delfosse"></category></entry><entry><title>Anton Krupicka - Purpose</title><link href="/anton-krupicka-purpose.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/anton-krupicka-purpose.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;La Sportiva presents &amp;quot;Purpose&amp;quot; a short movie dedicated to the Ultra-Runner and adventurer Anton Krupicka.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;La Sportiva presents &amp;quot;Purpose&amp;quot; a short movie dedicated to the Ultra-Runner and adventurer Anton Krupicka.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Anton Krupicka"></category></entry><entry><title>The Barkley Marathons: The Race That Eats Its Young</title><link href="/barkley-marathons-race-that-eats.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Timothy James Kane</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/barkley-marathons-race-that-eats.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A famous prison escape sparks the idea for a cult-like race that has seen only 10 finishers in its first 25 years. This award-winning, oddly...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A famous prison escape sparks the idea for a cult-like race that has seen only 10 finishers in its first 25 years. This award-winning, oddly inspiring, and wildly funny documentary reveals the sports world's most guarded secret.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="The Barkley Marathons"></category></entry><entry><title>Boston: The Documentary</title><link href="/boston-the-documentary.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Dunham</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/boston-the-documentary.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;From its humble origins 120 years ago to present day, Boston immerses the viewer into the wondrous kaleidoscope of the oldest annually contested...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From its humble origins 120 years ago to present day, Boston immerses the viewer into the wondrous kaleidoscope of the oldest annually contested marathon in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evolving from a workingman s challenge to welcoming foreign athletes and eventually women, the iconic race paved the way for the modern marathon and mass participatory sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Narrated by Academy Award® winner Matt Damon, Boston features many of running s greatest champions including Shalane Flanagan, Meb Keflezighi, Bill Rodgers, Frank Shorter and Joan Benoit Samuelson.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Jon Dunham"></category></entry><entry><title>Breaking 2</title><link href="/breaking-two.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Martin Roe</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/breaking-two.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;After six months of scientifically-advanced training, three of the world’s most elite distance runners set out to break the two-hour marathon...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After six months of scientifically-advanced training, three of the world’s most elite distance runners set out to break the two-hour marathon barrier. These pioneers go on a global trek to try to make history, from testing in wind tunnels and running labs in the U.S., to balancing training with their day-to-day lives in eastern Africa, to the final heart-pounding race in Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Brice, un vacher à l’assaut des Pyrénées</title><link href="/brice-un-vacher-a-l-assaut-des-pyrenees.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sandrine Mörch</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/brice-un-vacher-a-l-assaut-des-pyrenees.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Portrait d'un pâtre solitaire et marathonien de haut niveau. Depuis quatorze ans, Brice parcourt chaque été avec ses bêtes de vastes pâturages...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Portrait d'un pâtre solitaire et marathonien de haut niveau.
Depuis quatorze ans, Brice parcourt chaque été avec ses bêtes de vastes pâturages pyrénéens, à 3000 mètres d'altitude. Il a découvert dans l'immensité des Pyrénées la liberté ultime de courir jusqu'à l'épuisement sur des pentes raides, des crêtes escarpées, des terres rocailleuses et inhospitalières.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Brothers in the sand</title><link href="/brothers-in-the-sand.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tom Magnus</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/brothers-in-the-sand.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Five siblings attempt to become the first family in history to complete the Marathon Des Sables. But the world's toughest foot race pushes them to...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five siblings attempt to become the first family in history to complete the Marathon Des Sables. But the world's toughest foot race pushes them to confront much more than the landscape of the Sahara Desert, as they discover what their brotherhood means to them. Exploring depression, sibling rivalry, and - when one brother comes to the brink of failure - their bond as siblings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Desert Runners</title><link href="/desert-runners.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jennifer Steinman</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/desert-runners.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[amazon] A diverse cast of non-professional runners attempt to complete the most difficult ultra-marathon race series on Earth. Their dramatic...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[amazon] A diverse cast of non-professional runners attempt to complete the most difficult ultra-marathon race series on Earth. Their dramatic journey takes them across the world's most picturesque yet brutal landscapes, pushing their bodies, hearts and spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Entre terre et ciel</title><link href="/entre-ciel-et-terre.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Vincent Alix</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/entre-ciel-et-terre.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;French TV documentary on François d'Haene doing the 2018 Diagonale des fous.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;French TV documentary on François d'Haene doing the 2018 Diagonale des fous.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="La Diagonale des Fous"></category><category term="François d'Haene"></category></entry><entry><title>Finding The Limit. Big Backyard</title><link href="/finding-the-limit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/finding-the-limit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The documentary is about the pursuit of finding the limit in running. The concept seems almost too simple for the last-man-standing race, where...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The documentary is about the pursuit of finding the limit in running.
The concept seems almost too simple for the last-man-standing race, where runners have an hour to complete a 4.166667-mile trail loop during the day and a road loop at night. The loops repeat until there is one runner left, so having a plan of not quitting almost guarantees a victory.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Finding Traction</title><link href="/finding-traction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jaime Jacobsen</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/finding-traction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Ultra Runner Nikki Kimball takes on the 273-mile Long Trail. What drives someone to attempt such an incredible feat? Follow Nikki's journey from...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ultra Runner Nikki Kimball takes on the 273-mile Long Trail. What drives someone to attempt such an incredible feat? Follow Nikki's journey from its beginning to her actual record attempt through Vermont's beautiful but brutal Green Mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Found on 49 - The story of Jim Walmsley</title><link href="/found-on-49.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/found-on-49.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The story of Jim Walmsley's first 100 miler at the 2016 Western States 100 mile endurance run. We follow Jim a few weeks out from race day through...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The story of Jim Walmsley's first 100 miler at the 2016 Western States 100 mile endurance run. We follow Jim a few weeks out from race day through his historic day ahead of course record splits and the dramatic conclusion of being lost on highway 49.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Jim Walmsley"></category></entry><entry><title>François D’Haene, simple comme un ultra</title><link href="/francois-d-haene-simple-comme-un-ultra.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Paul Roumet</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/francois-d-haene-simple-comme-un-ultra.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;TV portrait of François d'Haene, ultra-runner but also a family man and wine maker.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;TV portrait of François d'Haene, ultra-runner but also a family man and wine maker.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="François d'Haene"></category></entry><entry><title>Free to Run</title><link href="/free-to-run.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Pierre Morath</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/free-to-run.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Today, all anybody needs to run is the determination and a pair of the right shoes. But just fifty years ago, running was viewed almost exclusively...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, all anybody needs to run is the determination and a pair of the right shoes. But just fifty years ago, running was viewed almost exclusively as the domain of elite male athletes who competed on tracks. With insight and propulsive energy, director Pierre Morath traces running&amp;amp;#xFFFD;&amp;amp;#x6EA;s rise to the 1960s, examining how the liberation movements and newfound sense of personal freedom that defined the era took the sport out of the stadiums and onto the streets, and how legends like Steve Prefontaine, Fred Lebow, and Kathrine Switzer redefined running as a populist phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Fred Lebow"></category><category term="Kathrine Switzer"></category></entry><entry><title>Golden hour - The Best Hour in Ultrarunning</title><link href="/golden-hour.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Austin Meyer</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/golden-hour.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The Western States 100-Mile Endurance Run is the world’s oldest 100-mile trail race. Starting in Olympic Valley, California it ends 100.2 miles...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Western States 100-Mile Endurance Run is the world’s oldest 100-mile trail race. Starting in Olympic Valley, California it ends 100.2 miles later in Auburn, California. Western States draws the top ultrarunners in the world, who can finish the race in under 15 hours. But perhaps the race’s most exhilarating finishes happen in double that time, as everyday people try to finish under the 30-hour time cutoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Known as the Golden Hour, the final hour of the race is a celebration of persistence, courage, and grit. It is what 7-time Western States top-10 finisher Andy Jones-Wilkins calls &amp;quot;the best hour in ultrarunning.&amp;quot; It is an hour that defines the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the story of Golden Hour.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category></entry><entry><title>Goshen</title><link href="/goshen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sarah Zentz</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/goshen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The Tarahumara tribe was made popular in Born to Run, a best-selling novel by Chris McDougall. GOSHEN is a powerful documentary depicting the diet...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Tarahumara tribe was made popular in Born to Run, a best-selling novel by Chris McDougall. GOSHEN is a powerful documentary depicting the diet and active lifestyle of the indigenous Tarahumara, a light-footed running tribe, who are striving to maintain their ancient culture against all odds. The Tarahumara are renowned for their incredible long-distance running endurance and prevention of modern chronic diseases. For centuries, the Tarahumara have found a safe place of refuge in the remote depths of Mexico’s Copper Canyons. Recently, drought and famine have threatened the Tarahumara’s ability to sustain their ancient cultural traditions. GOSHEN takes you on a journey in the huarache-clad footsteps of these endurance athletes, highlighting the health benefits of safeguarding their way of life. Engaging and entertaining, GOSHEN will inspire you to take part in preserving the native seeds and running traditions of the Tarahumara.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Gun Runners</title><link href="/gun-runners.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Anjali Nayar</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/gun-runners.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;When it comes to world-class marathon runners, Kenyans are considered the cream of the crop. But some of Kenya's top runners aren't running for...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to world-class marathon runners, Kenyans are considered the cream of the crop. But some of Kenya's top runners aren't running for fame and fortune. Some are wanted warriors, running for their lives. For years, Julius Arile and Robert Matanda thrived among the bands of warriors that terrorize the North Kenyan countryside. Stealing cattle, raiding and running from the police is the only life they knew. So when both warriors suddenly disappeared from the bush, many assumed they were dead or had been arrested. Instead, they traded in their rifles for sneakers in the hopes of making it big as professional marathon runners. Years of fleeing from the police have prepared the men for running marathon distances, but do they have what it takes to overcome the corruption, mistrust and jealousy that threaten to derail their careers? Told entirely by its central characters, Gun Runners is the American Dream, Kenyan-style.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Hardrunner</title><link href="/hardrunner.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Étienne Valentin</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/hardrunner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The Harkrock 100 is the perfect race to illustrate the difference between european ans US ultra-trail worlds. In this race there are only 140...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Harkrock 100 is the perfect race to illustrate the difference between european ans US ultra-trail worlds. In this race there are only 140 runners, no required equipment and 160km though a wild, high altitude natural landspace in Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Hardrock 100"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category><category term="Scott Jurek"></category><category term="Timothy Olson"></category><category term="Sébastien Chaigneau"></category><category term="Mouss films"></category><category term="Étienne Valentin"></category></entry><entry><title>Hood to coast</title><link href="/hood-to-coast.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marcie Hume</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/hood-to-coast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[Runner's World] Runners who have ever wanted to participate in the Hood to Coast relay, one of the largest of its kind in the world, might want to...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[Runner's World] Runners who have ever wanted to participate in the Hood to Coast relay, one of the largest of its kind in the world, might want to take a peek at the 2011 documentary about this popular race in Oregon. The relay is approximately 200 miles long and features more than a thousand 12-person teams, and the film chronicles four groups who ran in the 2008 race. Grab 12 of your closest running buddies, watch the film, and sign up. But it’s a very popular race, so don’t hesitate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>How To Run 100 Miles</title><link href="/how-to-run-100-miles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Brendan Leonard</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/how-to-run-100-miles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;In September 2017, I stepped up to the starting line of the Run Rabbit Run 100 in Steamboat Springs, Colorado, alongside my friend Jayson Sime. The...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In September 2017, I stepped up to the starting line of the Run Rabbit Run 100 in Steamboat Springs, Colorado, alongside my friend Jayson Sime. The race is a 102.9-mile ultramarathon with 20,000 feet of elevation gain, which is no small feat for a couple of guys who don’t know what they’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jayson had talked me into it, and if I were to be completely honest, I’d say we were there to test out his life philosophy, which is basically that you can do anything you dream up, as long as you put in the work and refuse to quit. That ethic has worked for him in almost every other area of life, despite growing up in poverty, one of six children with no father, and dyslexia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the six months leading up to the race, we figured since we weren’t naturally talented runners, the best thing we could do is work hard. So we ran 50- to 70-mile weeks all summer, and went through a full range of feelings: fear, regret, sadness, FOMO, hunger, thirst, exhaustion, pain, and joy. And gluttony, which is not a feeling, but what happens after you run 20 or more miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did the race go? You can watch our film, How to Run 100 Miles, to find out. No spoilers here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Indulgence: 1000 Miles Under the Colorado Sky</title><link href="/indulgence-1000.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alex Nichols</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/indulgence-1000.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The film details his training for that year’s Leadville 100 and his philosophy on ultrarunning in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The film details his training for that year’s Leadville 100 and his philosophy on ultrarunning in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Leadville 100"></category><category term="Anton Krupicka"></category></entry><entry><title>Into Patagonia With Dakota Jones</title><link href="/into-patagonia-with-dakota-jones.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dean Leslie</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/into-patagonia-with-dakota-jones.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Stretching in an unbroken sweep of agitated geology, Patagonia spans a massive area of over a million square kilometres and yet is home to less...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stretching in an unbroken sweep of agitated geology, Patagonia spans a massive area of over a million square kilometres and yet is home to less than two million people. With no clear objective and no set goal, American Alpine Runner, Dakota Jones, journeys to Northern Patagonia to explore the culture and landscape of one of the most romanticised regions in the world. Travelling South along the famed Carretera Austral he discovers a people rich in smiles and a land littered with mountains and glaciers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Salomon"></category><category term="The african attachment"></category><category term="Dean Leslie"></category></entry><entry><title>Into the wind</title><link href="/into-the-wind.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ezra Holland</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/into-the-wind.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[wikipedia] Into the Wind is a 2010 documentary film which chronicles the story of Terry Fox. At the age of 18, Fox was diagnosed with...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[wikipedia] Into the Wind is a 2010 documentary film which chronicles the story of Terry Fox. At the age of 18, Fox was diagnosed with osteosarcoma. The cancer had taken over his right leg, which was then amputated six inches above the knee. However, three years later, Fox set out to raise funds for cancer research and raise awareness by running 30 miles a day from the Atlantic Ocean in Newfoundland to the Pacific Ocean in British Columbia, totaling over 4000 miles.[1] The film was directed by the NBA star Steve Nash who grew up in Canada and followed Fox's run across the country as a kid in 1980, and narrated by Taylor Kitsch. Two thirds across Canada, Fox was once again diagnosed with cancer, which had spread to his lungs.[2] Fox died at the age of 22, inspiring the Terry Fox Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="Terry Fox"></category></entry><entry><title>John Muir Trail</title><link href="/john-muir-trail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Nico Favre</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/john-muir-trail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Ultratrail has always been Francois' main excuse or reason to drop everything and leave on a new adventure. For this to happen, he tries to broaden...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ultratrail has always been Francois' main excuse or reason to drop everything and leave on a new adventure. For this to happen, he tries to broaden his horizons with a new trail or destination every time. After completing the GR20, little were the options to top it off. Then came the idea of the John Muir Trail or JMT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMT presents many challenges: its distamce, the isolation and the altitude, to name only a few,make it one of the most beautiful trail in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attempting to run 350km of single trail crossing the isolated and mystic mountains of the Sierra Nevada is no small feat. Do it in a single shot and that's what legends are made of.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="John Muir Trail"></category><category term="François d'Haene"></category><category term="Salomon"></category></entry><entry><title>Kilian</title><link href="/kilian.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Mike Douglas</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/kilian.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Kilian Jornet is considered the greatest mountain runner ever. But he doesn't consider himself a runner. Join Kilian in his new backyard in Norway...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kilian Jornet is considered the greatest mountain runner ever. But he doesn't consider himself a runner. Join Kilian in his new backyard in Norway as he attempts to ski and run in a single day the Seven Summits of Romsdalen, a 77km route with 9000m of elevation gain.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category><category term="Salomon"></category></entry><entry><title>Kroger’s Canteen</title><link href="/kroger-s-canteen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dean Leslie</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/kroger-s-canteen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;In 2014, Kilian Jornet won the Hard Rock 100 mile run through the San Juan’s of Colorado. Along the way he stopped at Kroger’s Canteen – an aid...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Kilian Jornet won the Hard Rock 100 mile run through the San Juan’s of Colorado.  Along the way he stopped at Kroger’s Canteen – an aid station perched on a tiny ledge, 13,100ft above sea level.
This is a story about that aid station, about the people that make it happen, and about the spirit one can only find at The Hard Rock 100.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Hardrock 100"></category><category term="David Horton"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category><category term="Salomon"></category><category term="The african attachment"></category><category term="Dean Leslie"></category></entry><entry><title>La Barkley sans pitié</title><link href="/la-barkley-sans-pitie.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Aurélien Delfosse</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/la-barkley-sans-pitie.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;TV documentary on the Barkley Marathons.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;TV documentary on the Barkley Marathons.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="The Barkley Marathons"></category><category term="Gary Robbins"></category><category term="L´Equipe"></category><category term="Aurélien Delfosse"></category><category term="Alexis Berg"></category></entry><entry><title>La marche intérieure</title><link href="/la-marche-interieure.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Didier Lafond</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/la-marche-interieure.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Short tv documentary on the 2008 edition of UTMB, the first edition won by a 21 year old Kilian Jornet. This films also shows the adventure of all...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short tv documentary on the 2008 edition of UTMB, the first edition won by a 21 year old Kilian Jornet. This films also shows the adventure of all the middle and back of the pack runnings, that spend two nights on the Mont Blanc.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="UTMB"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category></entry><entry><title>Last Women Standing</title><link href="/last-women-standing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Matt Green</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/last-women-standing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;In 2019, inov-8 ambassador and breast cancer survivor Nicky Spinks attempted to become the first-ever woman to complete The Barkley Marathons - the...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2019, inov-8 ambassador and breast cancer survivor Nicky Spinks attempted to become the first-ever woman to complete The Barkley Marathons - the world's toughest ultra-running race. This film tells the story of Nicky, and her fellow female runners, as they battle treacherous terrain, wild weather and the twisted mind of Barkley Marathons organiser, Lazarus Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="The Barkley Marathons"></category><category term="Nicky Spinks"></category><category term="Inov-8"></category><category term="Summit Fever Media"></category><category term="Matt Green"></category><category term="Elie Green"></category></entry><entry><title>Le secret des Templiers</title><link href="/le-secret-des-templiers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Cyrielle Funch</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/le-secret-des-templiers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Le Festival des Templiers est l’un des premiers événements de trail en France au cœur des grands Causses des Cévennes. Dans ce film, les athlètes...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Le Festival des Templiers est l’un des premiers événements de trail en France au cœur des grands Causses des Cévennes. Dans ce film, les athlètes Sylvaine Cussot et Christian Vignaud, racontent leur passion pour la course en sentier à travers le Grand Trail des Templiers, une épreuve de 78 km et 3650 m de D+.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Mouss films"></category><category term="Étienne Valentin"></category></entry><entry><title>LEADMAN: The Dave Mackey Story</title><link href="/leadman.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/leadman.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;On May 23, 2015, the unimaginable happened to Altra Running and CamelBak athlete Dave Mackey on a routine training run. At the summit of Bear Peak,...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On May 23, 2015, the unimaginable happened to Altra Running and CamelBak athlete Dave Mackey on a routine training run. At the summit of Bear Peak, a giant boulder became dislodged sending Mackey tumbling down the mountain before it also landed on him crushing his left leg. After a series of unsuccessful surgeries over the next year plus to get back to normal, he and his family made the difficult decision to amputate. This is his story about perseverance and coming back from the injury to attempting to complete the Leadville Race Series to become the first ever leg amputee to call himself a &amp;quot;Leadman&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>Life in a day</title><link href="/life-in-a-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/life-in-a-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;On June 25, 2016 a collection of trail and ultra runners toed the line at the historic Western States 100 Mile Endurance Run running from Squaw...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 25, 2016 a collection of trail and ultra runners toed the line at the historic Western States 100 Mile Endurance Run running from Squaw Valley to Auburn. Among the 350+ were 4 women vying for the win and a coveted top 10 finish which is recognized annually at this prestigious event:
Magdalena Boulet, a HOKA ONE ONE and GU ENERGY LABS athlete is the returning champion and a mother of one who lives and trains in the East Bay of Northern California. She has an incredible road background including earning a trip to the Olympics in 2008 by placing 2nd at the Olympic Trials. (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.magdaboulet.com/"&gt;https://www.magdaboulet.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &amp;#64;RunBoulet)
Devon Yanko is also a HOKA ONE ONE athlete and has excelled in many different ultra distances. This is her 2nd attempt at the Western States 100 Mile Race with her 1st resulting in a DNF, or Did Not Finish. She is the co-owner of MH Bread &amp;amp; Butter in San Anselmo, CA along with her husband Nathan. (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.devonyanko.com/"&gt;http://www.devonyanko.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &amp;#64;fast_foodie)
Kaci Lickteig placed 2nd in the 2015 running of the Western States 100 is among the favorites to win it. She hails from Omaha, Nebraska where she works as an in-patient physical therapist. (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pixieninjarunning.blogspot.com/"&gt;http://pixieninjarunning.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt; | &amp;#64;ultrarunnerkc)
Anna Mae Flynn of Lake Tahoe, CA is going for her 1st 100 mile attempt after gaining entry via a golden ticket slot at the Lake Sonoma 50 Mile Race in 2016. She is a teacher and a recent ultra athlete. (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/flynnannamae/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/flynnannamae/&lt;/a&gt; | &amp;#64;annamaeflynn on Instagram, &amp;#64;amflynnrunner on Twitter)
This is a story of their 100 mile journey of which the great Ann Trason compares to living a &amp;quot;life in a day&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Magdalena Boulet"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>Live on your own terms</title><link href="/live-on-your-own-terms.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/live-on-your-own-terms.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;“I understand there’s a guy inside me who wants to lay in bed, smoke weed all day, and watch cartoons and old movies. My whole life is a series of...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“I understand there’s a guy inside me who wants to lay in bed, smoke weed all day, and watch cartoons and old movies. My whole life is a series of stratagems to avoid, and outwit, that guy.” -Anthony Bourdain&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>Lorena, Light-Footed Woman</title><link href="/lorena.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Juan Carlos Rulfo</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/lorena.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Lorena Ramírez of Mexico's Rarámuri community lives a pastoral life -- except when she straps on her sandals to compete as an ultramarathon runner.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lorena Ramírez of Mexico's Rarámuri community lives a pastoral life -- except when she straps on her sandals to compete as an ultramarathon runner.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Tarahumara"></category></entry><entry><title>Karl Meltzer: Made to be Broken</title><link href="/made-to-be-broken.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Mat Katsolis</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/made-to-be-broken.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Ultrarunner Karl Meltzer has long dreamed of setting the speed record for crossing the USA's Appalachian Trail. This is his third and final attempt...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ultrarunner Karl Meltzer has long dreamed of setting the speed record for crossing the USA's Appalachian Trail. This is his third and final attempt to run the 3,524km (2,188 miles) in record time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Appalachian Trail"></category></entry><entry><title>Mentors: Hillary Allen</title><link href="/metors-hillary-allen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/metors-hillary-allen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;After a harrowing accident, ultra runner Hillary Allen began a journey to recovery that allowed her to discover the true meaning of strength.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a harrowing accident, ultra runner Hillary Allen began a journey to recovery that allowed her to discover the true meaning of strength.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="The North Face"></category></entry><entry><title>Mira</title><link href="/mira.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Lloyd Belcher</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/mira.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Mira’ retrace le parcourt d’une jeune villageoise népalaise dont l’objectif est de devenir une coureuse mondialement reconnue. Originaire d’un...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mira’ retrace le parcourt d’une jeune villageoise népalaise dont l’objectif est de devenir une coureuse mondialement reconnue.
Originaire d’un village de montagne dans une zone reculée du Népal, Mira a toujours rêvé d’être une grande sportive malgré les difficultés auxquelles, comme toutes les Népalaises, elle est confrontée. Après avoir quitté ses parents et rejoint les rangs de l’armée maoïste jusqu’à la fin de son adolescence, Mira a ensuite tenté de percer dans le sport en ralliant la lointaine Katmandou. A court d’argent et sur le point de rentrer chez elle, au cours d’un entrainement matinal elle tombe sur un coureur qui lui parle d’une course dans les collines avoisinantes. Mira la remporte et réalise que la rudesse de son enfance dans les montagnes l’a préparée à exceller dans cette discipline.
Cette histoire filmée au Népal, à Hong Kong, en Australie, en Espagne en Italie raconte le parcourt de Mira, prête à tout pour concourir face aux meilleurs coureurs d’ultra-trail du monde.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Never Die Easy - The 'Most Elusive' Man in North America</title><link href="/never-die-easy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Justin Pelletier</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/never-die-easy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Dag Aabye is a septuagenarian Ultra Marathon champion who lives completely off the grid. Can two filmmakers track him down—and if so, what will...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dag Aabye is a septuagenarian Ultra Marathon champion who lives completely off the grid. Can two filmmakers track him down—and if so, what will they find?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Origines - Une traversée du GR4</title><link href="/origines.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Étienne Valentin</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/origines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;When trail running is a way to discover one's own back yard.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When trail running is a way to discover one's own back yard.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Mouss films"></category><category term="Étienne Valentin"></category></entry><entry><title>Out There - A Journey to the Barkley Marathons</title><link href="/out-there.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Fabien Duflos</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/out-there.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The Barkley Marathons - one of the world's toughest ultramarathons, has been held annually in the Frozen Head State Park, Tennessee, since 1987....&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Barkley Marathons - one of the world's toughest ultramarathons, has been held annually in the Frozen Head State Park, Tennessee, since 1987.
The race is so brutal that, since the inception of the race, only 15 people have managed to finish. Runners are to run five 20-mile loops, within a 60 hour time limit and with more than 20.000m of elevation change.
The course is unmarked, no electronic devices are allowed and most of the race is off-trail.
Out There - A journey to the Barkley Marathons is the story of Belgian ultrarunner Karel Sabbe, who holds the world records on two of the most epic trails in the world: the 4279km long Pacific Crest Trail and the 3500km long Appalachian Trail.
How did setting these world records prepare Karel for a race as brutal as &amp;quot;the Barkley&amp;quot;? How did these adventures help Karel to find the necessary mindset to do well at this Spartan challenge?
Out There is a story of persistence, endurance and a passion for the great outdoors, and the film inspires the audience to reconnect with nature and to find courage for personal challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="The Barkley Marathons"></category></entry><entry><title>Pacing Hardrock</title><link href="/pacing-hardrock.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Pelletier</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/pacing-hardrock.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Pacing Hardrock tells Jeff Pelletier’s story of pacing his friend Kevin Douglas at 2015 Hardrock 100. The film provides a glimpse of not only the...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pacing Hardrock tells Jeff Pelletier’s story of pacing his friend Kevin Douglas at 2015 Hardrock 100. The film provides a glimpse of not only the race itself, but of the unique atmosphere and events surrounding the race in the historic mountain town of Silverton, Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Hardrock 100"></category></entry><entry><title>Parti en diagonale (Grand Raid 2013)</title><link href="/parti-en-diagonale.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alexis Berg</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/parti-en-diagonale.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;&amp;quot;La Diagonale des fous. Son nom dit tout ou presque. Cet ultra-trail tropical qui emprunte depuis plus de 20 ans le cadre unique et magique de...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;La Diagonale des fous. Son nom dit tout ou presque. Cet ultra-trail tropical qui emprunte depuis plus de 20 ans le cadre unique et magique de l'île de La Réunion a parcouru cette année, en 2013, près de 170 km et gravit 10 000 mètres de dénivelé positif. Elle a entraîné dans sa danse intense plus de 2000 « fous ». On l'a dit une des courses à pied les plus dures au monde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce défi sportif et humain revêt une signification différente pour chacun, un sens particulier pour chaque femme, chaque homme qui prend le départ. Pour moi, Frédéric, né le 1er septembre 1971 à Besançon, l'aventure c'est d'aller au bout, de vivre pleinement ce moment où les souffrances sont balayées par une magie qui confine à la poésie. Courir, marcher, souffrir, penser, divaguer, délirer... pour se sentir vivre. Maladivement. Follement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce film réalisé par mon frère Alexis est un témoignage. C'est le partage de deux frères qui se comprennent à la seconde sans trop se parler, c'est un regard posé par lui sur mon envie de transmettre par-dessus les mots. Transmettre ce modeste message  -- au bout de chaque tunnel il y a une lumière et putain qu'elle peut être belle cette lueur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merci à tous ceux qui m'ont aidé. Merci à lui et vive la folie quand elle court sur les plus beaux sentiers de la planète...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frédéric, dossard 1331.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="La Diagonale des Fous"></category><category term="Alexis Berg"></category></entry><entry><title>Path to everest</title><link href="/path-to-everest.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc Juan</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/path-to-everest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;When he was a child Kilian Jornet, the world's greatest ever mountain runner, made a list of all the races he wanted to win and all the mountains...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When he was a child Kilian Jornet, the world's greatest ever mountain runner, made a list of all the races he wanted to win and all the mountains he dreamt of climbing.  The documentary tells the story of how Kilian Jornet, the world's greatest ever mountain runner, succeeded in completing the historic double ascent of Everest in one week, alone and without oxygen in May 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category></entry><entry><title>Paul Braa – Western States 100</title><link href="/paul-braa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/paul-braa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;After watching endless documentaries about elites running Western States, it’s nice to watch the “average joes” getting it done. I stumbled upon...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After watching endless documentaries about elites running Western States, it’s nice to watch the “average joes” getting it done. I stumbled upon this one while falling down the rabbit hole of YouTube, and I just loved it.  Not only is the soundtrack awesome, but Paul Braa’s enthusiasm about finally making it to the race of his dreams is contagious.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category></entry><entry><title>Profiling HURT</title><link href="/profiling-hurt.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Barry Walton</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/profiling-hurt.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Profiling HURT follows the path of ultra runner Mark Gilligan and his work to return to the race for a second year, to achieve what he couldn't in...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Profiling HURT follows the path of ultra runner Mark Gilligan and his work to return to the race for a second year, to achieve what he couldn't in his first. Joined by protagonist Scott Guild, the two take you to the course and drop you in the middle of it all so you can see what it's all about. Mud, injuries, training runs, and drop outs. It's not just a race for the finish, it's a battle to know how far you can go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Run for your life</title><link href="/run-for-your-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Judd Ehrilich</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/run-for-your-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Without one eccentric, first-generation Jewish immigrant from Transylvania, the New York City Marathon simply wouldn't exist. Ehrlich's fun, loving...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Without one eccentric, first-generation Jewish immigrant from Transylvania, the New York City Marathon simply wouldn't exist. Ehrlich's fun, loving and inspirational tribute to the late Fred Lebow shows how one man's imagination, determination and love for running created one of the world's most popular sporting events.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Fred Lebow"></category></entry><entry><title>Run Forever: The film of Nicky Spinks &amp; The Double Bob Graham</title><link href="/run-forever-nicky-spinks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Nick Brown</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/run-forever-nicky-spinks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;the award-winning film about inspirational runner Nicky Spinks and her incredible attempt at the 132-mile Double Bob Graham Round.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;the award-winning film about inspirational runner Nicky Spinks and her incredible attempt at the 132-mile Double Bob Graham Round.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Nicky Spinks"></category><category term="Inov-8"></category></entry><entry><title>Run Free: The True Story of Caballo Blanco</title><link href="/run-free-the-true-story-caballo-blanco.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sterling Noren</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/run-free-the-true-story-caballo-blanco.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Run Free is a movie about Micah True (Caballo Blanco, or the White Horse), an American ultra runner who helped the Tarahumara Indians of Mexico...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Run Free is a movie about Micah True (Caballo Blanco, or the White Horse), an American ultra runner who helped the Tarahumara Indians of Mexico preserve their traditional running culture by creating a 50-mile ultra marathon which combines aspects of traditional Tarahumara running with the ideology of modern ultra running.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Scott Jurek"></category><category term="Tarahumara"></category></entry><entry><title>Runner</title><link href="/runner.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Bill Gallagher</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/runner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A touching story about a runner from Sudan that went from refugee to Olympian.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A touching story about a runner from Sudan that went from refugee to Olympian.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Running America</title><link href="/running-america.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Kerwin</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-america.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Charlie Engle (from Running the Sahara) and Ultra-Marathoner Marshall Ulrich press the human physical and mental strengths to their limits in a run...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charlie Engle (from Running the Sahara) and Ultra-Marathoner Marshall Ulrich press the human physical and mental strengths to their limits in a run from San Francisco to Times Square.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="US Transcontinental"></category><category term="Charlie Engle"></category></entry><entry><title>Running For Freedom: My Journey as an Ultra Marathon Runner</title><link href="/running-for-freedom.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>James Castillo</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-for-freedom.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Gerald Tabios, Filipino Ultra Runner, runs his 5th Badwater 135, considered as the world's toughest footrace. Together with his crew, Gerald has to...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gerald Tabios, Filipino Ultra Runner, runs his 5th Badwater 135, considered as the world's toughest footrace. Together with his crew, Gerald has to run 2 deserts, climb 3 mountains, run 135 miles during record-breaking heat across Death Valley within 48 hrs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Badwater 135"></category></entry><entry><title>Running Madness</title><link href="/running-madness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Susan Cohn Schultz</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-madness.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;&amp;quot;Vintage&amp;quot; documentary on Western States 100. Focuses on &amp;quot;average joes&amp;quot;, and features a very young, long haired Scott Jurek. Great stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Vintage&amp;quot; documentary on Western States 100. Focuses on &amp;quot;average joes&amp;quot;, and features a very young, long haired Scott Jurek. Great stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2000-2004"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Scott Jurek"></category></entry><entry><title>Running On Empty ft. Rory Bosio</title><link href="/running-on-empty.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-on-empty.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Revivez la traversée du GR20 en Corse par la championne américaine d’ultra-trail Rory Bosio, double vainqueure de l’UTMB, en 2013 (record de...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Revivez la traversée du GR20 en Corse par la championne américaine d’ultra-trail Rory Bosio, double vainqueure de l’UTMB, en 2013 (record de l’épreuve en 22 h 37) et 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="The North Face"></category></entry><entry><title>Running on the Sun</title><link href="/running-on-the-sun.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Mel Stuart</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-on-the-sun.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Feature-length documentary about the 1999 Badwater Ultramarathon. This legendary, epic, 135 mile running race travels non-stop in the heat of...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Feature-length documentary about the 1999 Badwater Ultramarathon.  This legendary, epic, 135 mile running race travels non-stop in the heat of Summer from Badwater in Death Valley (elev. 282 feet below sea level) to Whitney Portal on Mt. Whitney (elev. 8360 feet). Field size is limited to up to 90 runners.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="x-1999"></category><category term="Badwater 135"></category></entry><entry><title>Running the Sahara</title><link href="/running-the-sahara.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>James Moll</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-the-sahara.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;This inspirational film chronicles three ultra marathoners' attempt to run the entire length of Africa's Sahara Desert.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This inspirational film chronicles three ultra marathoners' attempt to run the entire length of Africa's Sahara Desert.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Charlie Engle"></category></entry><entry><title>Paul Tierney: Running The Wainwrights</title><link href="/running-the-wainwrights.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave MacFarlane</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/running-the-wainwrights.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;In June 2019, inov-8 ambassador Paul Tierney set out on an epic adventure to summit all 214 Alfred Wainwright Lake District peaks in one go. His...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In June 2019, inov-8 ambassador Paul Tierney set out on an epic adventure to summit all 214 Alfred Wainwright Lake District peaks in one go. His goal was to try and beat the record time of 6 days 13 hours and 1 minute, set five years earlier by fellow fell runner Steve Birkinshaw.
Needing to cover a distance of approximately 318 miles and ascend the equivalent height of four times Mt Everest, Paul knew this was his biggest challenge to date and enlisted the help of friends and family.
Battling sleep deprivation and everything the Lake District weather could throw at him, what transpired was a story that gripped not only the fell-running and ultra-running communities but also the wider sporting world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Inov-8"></category></entry><entry><title>Showing Up</title><link href="/showing-up.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Scura</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/showing-up.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The documentary film will take you in-depth into the lives of 8 athletes who collectively tell the story of community, identity, and why it matters...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The documentary film will take you in-depth into the lives of 8 athletes who collectively tell the story of community, identity, and why it matters to be a part of something transformative. November Project, the Free Fitness Movement that started in Boston that is now taking over the world, is simply the vessel for these stories. Laugh, cry, train, support, repeat. Please view, share, and talk to strangers out there in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="The North Face"></category></entry><entry><title>Skid Row Marathon</title><link href="/skid-row-marathon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Mark Hayes</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/skid-row-marathon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Skid Row Marathon is the uplifting and inspiring story of an unlikely group of individuals from LA's Skid Row, who receive a second chance at life,...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Skid Row Marathon is the uplifting and inspiring story of an unlikely group of individuals from LA's Skid Row, who receive a second chance at life, all brought on by a simple act of kindness.
Follow the story of High Court Judge, Craig Mitchell as he coaches a long-distance running club from the Midnight Mission on Skid Row. Using the redemptive power of running and the camaraderie of the group, marathon training raises the spirits of Skid Row's inhabitants and gives a sense of purpose to a group of people who are homeless, addicted or coming out of the prison system.
&amp;quot;One horrendous act does not define a person in his entirety&amp;quot; and so the film highlights the transformation of homeless and often helpless individuals into sober, rounded and functioning members of society.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>Spirit of the Marathon</title><link href="/spirit-of-the-marathon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Dunham</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/spirit-of-the-marathon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[wikipedia] Spirit of the Marathon is a 2007 documentary film directed by Jon Dunham. The film chronicles the journey six marathon runners...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[wikipedia] Spirit of the Marathon is a 2007 documentary film directed by Jon Dunham. The film chronicles the journey six marathon runners experience while training and competing in the 2005 Chicago Marathon. It was screened at the Chicago International Film Festival on October 5, 2007 and received a limited release in the United States on January 24, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Jon Dunham"></category></entry><entry><title>Spirit of the Marathon II</title><link href="/spirit-of-the-marathon-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Dunham</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/spirit-of-the-marathon-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;From the producers of the award-winning documentary Spirit of the Marathon, this highly-anticipated sequel follows seven runners from around the...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the producers of the award-winning documentary Spirit of the Marathon, this highly-anticipated sequel follows seven runners from around the world as they journey to the starting line of the Rome Marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spirit of the Marathon II weaves the compelling stories of each runner – the trials and the triumphs – that paved their road to Rome. The documentary also features insightful interviews with marathon greats such as Stefano Baldini, Paula Radcliffe, Frank Shorter, and many others, as they offer perspective and insight into this legendary race.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Jon Dunham"></category></entry><entry><title>STRINGBEAN - Appalachian Trail FKT Documentary</title><link href="/stringbean.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Joe McConaughy</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/stringbean.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Stringbean tells the story of ultrarunner Joe McConaughy as he attempts to break the speed record on the Appalachian Trail. It takes most hikers...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stringbean tells the story of ultrarunner Joe McConaughy as he attempts to break the speed record on the Appalachian Trail. It takes most hikers 5-6 months to complete the 2,190-mile-long trail, but in the summer of 2017, Joe set out to hike it in 45 days. This short documentary offers a raw look at life on the trail from Joe’s perspective, as he tries to hike 50 miles a day for 45 consecutive days on America's most iconic long trail.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Appalachian Trail"></category></entry><entry><title>Terry Fox Remembered</title><link href="/terry-fox-remembered.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jim Eidt</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/terry-fox-remembered.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Beyond the funds raised for cancer research, Terry Fox and his Marathon of Hope left another, less visible legacy: a profound impact on the lives...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beyond the funds raised for cancer research, Terry Fox and his Marathon of Hope left another, less visible legacy: a profound impact on the lives of the thousands who crossed paths with the courageous young runner. These people remember Terry, not from television or newspaper reports, but from personal experience. For most, it was an unforgettable meeting. For many, it was an encounter that changed their lives forever. Terry Fox Remembered is their story.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="Terry Fox"></category></entry><entry><title>Thabang</title><link href="/thabang.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dean Leslie</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/thabang.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Thabang Madiba somehow found his way into the world of trail running and in the last few years has become everyone’s favourite in the South African...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thabang Madiba somehow found his way into the world of trail running and in the last few years has become everyone’s favourite in the South African trail scene. He lives in Ga-Rankuwa township, without a mountain in sight… or a physio, chiro or dietician for that matter.  But through hard work, dedication and passion, he has won the South African Trail Running Championships multiple times and was the first black South African to represent the country in Trail Running. He has become a hero in his community and is hoping to inspire a new generation of youth through the sport of trail running.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Salomon"></category><category term="The Wandering Fever"></category><category term="Dean Leslie"></category></entry><entry><title>The 100 Mile King</title><link href="/the-100-mile-king.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-100-mile-king.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A fun and lighthearted film about the incredible and inspirational 29 hour run of the oldest finisher in Western States Endurance Run history, Nick...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A fun and lighthearted film about the incredible and inspirational 29 hour run of the oldest finisher in Western States Endurance Run history, Nick Bassett.  I can only hope to still be running, never mind running sub 30 hour 100 milers, at his age!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category></entry><entry><title>The 41st Day</title><link href="/the-41st-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tim Jeffries</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-41st-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Ryan Hall is the fastest marathon runner in American history. His consistency is only matched by legends of the sport. In order to go down as the...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ryan Hall is the fastest marathon runner in American history. His consistency is only matched by legends of the sport. In order to go down as the best, however, Ryan needs to do something that has eluded him his whole career - win an international marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This August, Ryan will try to do that in the biggest race of his life, the 2012 Olympic Marathon. He will take on the dominant east Africans and the rest of the world in a race that is being billed as the toughest and fastest in Olympic history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryan isn't the ordinary runner, though. While competitors prepare in training groups under the systematic care of coaches and advisors, Ryan runs alone. Practicing what he calls faith-based coaching, he relies exclusively on the direction of his faith to dictate his training, an unprecedented and often scrutinized approach in the world of distance running. &amp;quot;For me, running is an art more than a science,&amp;quot; says Ryan. One can't argue with his results up to this point, but will his faith be enough to take him to the top?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This film will tell his story.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>The Great American Foot Race</title><link href="/the-great-american-footrace.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Lily Shangreaux</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-great-american-footrace.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Facing scorching temperatures, 19-year-old Andy Payne, a small-town Cherokee boy, takes home the gold after winning a grueling 3,422-mile foot race...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Facing scorching temperatures, 19-year-old Andy Payne, a small-town Cherokee boy, takes home the gold after winning a grueling 3,422-mile foot race designed to bring attention to the newly constructed Route 66 Highway.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2000-2004"></category><category term="US Transcontinental"></category></entry><entry><title>The Human Race</title><link href="/the-human-race.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Liz Vassey</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-human-race.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;[Runner's World] Everyone has a reason for why they run, and this film shares a handful of those stories in inspiring fashion. The documentary...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[Runner's World] Everyone has a reason for why they run, and this film shares a handful of those stories in inspiring fashion. The documentary spotlights six runners over the age of 50—including a father attempting his very first 5K with his autistic son by his side, running revolutionary Kathrine Switzer, and an 80-year-old running a half marathon in celebration of her birthday—as they train for a monumental race. If you need a reminder that you can accomplish any goal you set your mind to, no matter your age or experience, this is one to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[official] THE HUMAN RACE is an inspirational full-length documentary about six runners, all over the age of 50, as they each train for the biggest race of their lives. These six athletes cover quite the spectrum: from a father attempting his very first 5K - with his autistic son by his side, to beloved running icon Kathrine Switzer who, in 1967, became the first woman to officially run the Boston Marathon as a numbered entry, to an 80-year-old running a half-marathon in celebration of her birthday, to a cancer survivor's attempt to run across all fifty states. We'll find out what motivates them to keep going, we'll delve deeply into their various training programs, and we'll follow them all the way to the finish line - while getting to know their colorful personalities and gaining insight on how running has helped them through various struggles. Make no mistake, this documentary is not &amp;quot;cute.&amp;quot; These runners are dedicated, fierce, competitive...and they could probably outrun you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Kathrine Switzer"></category></entry><entry><title>The Long Haul: John Muir Trail (Hal Koerner and Mike Wolfe)</title><link href="/the-long-haul.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>JB Benna</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-long-haul.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;JB Benna's short film recounts the story of Ultramarathoners Mike Wolfe and Hal Koerner as they set out to run the John Muir Trail in 2013 and best...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;JB Benna's short film recounts the story of Ultramarathoners Mike Wolfe and Hal Koerner as they set out to run the John Muir Trail in 2013 and best the previously record of 3 Days, 14 hours. The film features interviews with previous record holders and shares the history of this grueling feat. See the beauty, purity and ruggedness of the Sierra Nevada Mountains through their eyes as they struggle to complete this monumental and historic task.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="John Muir Trail"></category><category term="JourneyFilm"></category><category term="JB Benna"></category></entry><entry><title>The Musician</title><link href="/the-musician.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dean Leslie</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-musician.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Ben Gibbard is the frontman for American alternative rock band “Death Cab for Cutie”, he also happens to love trail running. We linked up with him...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ben Gibbard is the frontman for American alternative rock band “Death Cab for Cutie”, he also happens to love trail running.  We linked up with him for a week during DCFC’s 2015 US tour and got to know a bit more about his passion and love for the trails and music.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Salomon"></category><category term="Dean Leslie"></category></entry><entry><title>The Runner: David Horton's 2700 Mile Run of the Pacific Crest Trail</title><link href="/the-runner.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>JB Benna</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-runner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;June 2005 - The Runner follows Extreme UltraRunner David Horton through the desert sun, the high snowbound mountain passes, the pain, the emotion,...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;June 2005 - The Runner follows Extreme UltraRunner David Horton through the desert sun, the high snowbound mountain passes, the pain, the emotion, and his revelation. Join him as he runs more than 40 miles per day for 66 consecutive days in an attempt to set the speed record on the 2,700 mile Pacific Crest Trail from Mexico to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="David Horton"></category><category term="JourneyFilm"></category><category term="JB Benna"></category></entry><entry><title>The running pastor</title><link href="/the-running-pastor.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tim Kemple</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-running-pastor.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Sverri Steinholm grew up chasing sheep up and down the rugged, exposed slopes of the Faroe Islands. Today he is a pastor of the Lutheran Church,...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sverri Steinholm grew up chasing sheep up and down the rugged, exposed slopes of the Faroe Islands. Today he is a pastor of the Lutheran Church, the dominant religion on the island. He is also a compulsive runner, finding solace and spiritual refuge from personal conflicts and the burdens of priesthood on the trails and roads of his homeland. He may inhabit a very different world, but his words will ring true to anyone who has found peace in nature. “Somehow I am driven to it,” he says. “The body needs it, or my soul, my mind.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>The source</title><link href="/the-source.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tim HIghman</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-source.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The Source is a documentary film that explores elite ultra runner Courtney Dauwalter's source of will. How does the candy-loving, beer drinking...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Source is a documentary film that explores elite ultra runner Courtney Dauwalter's source of will. How does the candy-loving, beer drinking athlete crush 200+ mile races, in some cases, beating all the men and the women?
The film gives viewers a front row seat as Courtney races the Tahoe 200 and lends insight.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>The Teacher</title><link href="/the-teacher.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dean Leslie</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-teacher.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Stevie Kremer is a second grade teacher from the small idyllic mountain town of Crested Butte, Colorado. She also happens to be considered one of...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stevie Kremer is a second grade teacher from the small idyllic mountain town of Crested Butte, Colorado. She also happens to be considered one of the worlds top trail runners. In this episode she gives us a glimpse into balancing her life, her competitive streak and her love for teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Salomon"></category><category term="The african attachment"></category><category term="Dean Leslie"></category></entry><entry><title>Great Himalaya Trail, High Route – The Ultimate Trail</title><link href="/the-ultimate-trail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Anna Gatta</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-ultimate-trail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;In September 2013, Philippe and Anna Gatta left the small village of Simikot in the Western Nepal, aiming to run the high route of the Great...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In September 2013, Philippe and Anna Gatta left the small village of Simikot in the Western Nepal, aiming to run the high route of the Great Himalaya Trail in less than 40 days. Running the High Route in less than 40 days is the equivalent of 40 marathons in 40 days with 15 passes over 5,000 meters and two over 6,000m. This film tells their story.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>THE UNKNOWN | The Hardrock 100</title><link href="/the-unknown.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-unknown.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;&amp;quot;You really have to embrace the unknown. You can try all you want to script it - how you see the day going and have these plans. But the mountains...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You really have to embrace the unknown. You can try all you want to script it - how you see the day going and have these plans. But the mountains don't care. They're indifferent to whatever plans, whatever hopes you have...&amp;quot;
The 2016 Hardrock 100 was supposed to be a redemption race. In 2014, The North Face athlete Timothy Olson hit a figurative brick wall halfway through The Hardrock and was reduced to lying on the ground, sick and unable to continue for awhile. He eventually finished but wanted to prove to himself he could do better. He got that opportunity in 2016 when he was selected to run the race again.
Unfortunately for Timothy, deja vu would rear its ugly head and a similar fate awaited him at the Hardrock...&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Hardrock 100"></category><category term="Timothy Olson"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>THE WHY | Running 100 Miles</title><link href="/the-why.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Billy Yang</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-why.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Why do we run 100 miles? It's a question I get from friends and acquaintances quite often. And in the lower moments during these ultramarathon...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Why do we run 100 miles?
It's a question I get from friends and acquaintances quite often. And in the lower moments during these ultramarathon events if I'm honest, a question I direct inward too. Sure, on the surface you can cite self-improvement, challenging yourself, so on and so forth. But the longer I do this, the more I started to explore answers beyond the surface. How we relate to discomfort, uncertainty and pain. Do we have it too easy and thus, we're drawn to the opposite end of the spectrum where we're reduced to &amp;quot;survival&amp;quot; mode and drinking/eating/moving forward? Are we in our more natural state when this is what our world is reduced down to?
Using the historic and legendary Leadville 100 Mile Race as my backdrop and with the support of GU Energy Labs, I explore these ideas as I ran my 3rd 100-mile race at the &amp;quot;Race Across the Sky&amp;quot;. Through the good, bad and the ugly - I attempted to unpack &amp;quot;the why&amp;quot; in running a 100 miles. My thanks again to them for the support!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Leadville 100"></category><category term="Billy Yang Films"></category><category term="Billy Yang"></category></entry><entry><title>The worlds' highest running race - 222km</title><link href="/the-world-s-highest-race.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Wes Greene</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/the-world-s-highest-race.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Lisa Tamati takes you on a Himalayan adventure. The worlds' highest running race - known as La Ultra - The High is a 222km non stop running race...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lisa Tamati takes you on a Himalayan adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worlds' highest running race - known as La Ultra - The High is a 222km non stop running race over the two highest motorable mountain passes in the world.
Held in the Indian region of Ladakh (translated &amp;quot;The land of high passes&amp;quot;)  is a region in Indian state of Jammu and Kashmir that currently extends from the Kunlun mountain range  to the main Great Himalayas to the south, inhabited by people of Indo-Aryan and Tibetan descent.It is one of the most sparsely populated regions in Jammu and Kashmir and its culture and history are closely related to that of Tibet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past Ladakh gained importance from its strategic location at the crossroads of important trade routes, but since the Chinese authorities closed the borders with Tibet and Central Asia in the 1960s, international trade has dwindled but the Indian military maintains a strong hold there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year this incredibly tough ultra marathon is held. This is a documentary following Lisa Tamati racing it in its second year of running.
The first year only one man, Mark Cockbain, managed to finish and the other two competitors and some of the crew all ended up in hospital with altitude related problems
This race sees the competitors go  up twice within a very short time space to altitudes over 5,700m, climbing over the infamous Kardung La and Tanglang La passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxygen levels up there are around 30% of what they are at sea level making it extremely tough to get enough oxygen to run.
The terrain is mountainous, the rugged single lane roads frequented by military convoys spewing unfiltered diesel into the mountain air add to the difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competitors have extremes of temperature to deal with from 40 degrees celsius in the valleys to -3 in the mountains. This makes for slow going and there is more walking and running but don't underestimate how tough this is
Before Lisa even started she had a brain concussion to deal with a ripped ligaments on her left ankle ten weeks prior to going. Meaning she is undertrained and not well and during the race Lisa faces asthma attacks, heat exhaustion, severe altitude related problems, snow storms and treacherous roads to try and be the first woman to conquer this race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She ends up second behind the incredible Sharon Gayter from England but this 53hr and 5 minute odyssey will give the viewer a birdseye view on what its like to attempt something this mammoth, to face extreme fatigue, sleep deprivation and fear, altitude and health problems and to overcome and persevere against all odds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffer and celebrate with Lisa on this once in a life time journey&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Transamericana with Rickey Gates running 3700 miles across America</title><link href="/transamericana.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dean Leslie</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/transamericana.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;In a time of uncertain politics and a crescendo of differences, American Ultra-Runner Rickey Gates sets off on foot across America. In the midst of...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a time of uncertain politics and a crescendo of differences, American Ultra-Runner Rickey Gates sets off on foot across America. In the midst of the 2016 National Elections, which saw Republican candidate Donald Trump win the presidential elections, Gates realised that the America he knew wasn’t necessarily the America that was. Intrigued and curious, Gates decides to head out and see for himself in order to try understand and empathise with his fellow Americans. Starting out on the edge of the Atlantic Ocean in South Carolina, Gates journey takes him 5 months and nearly 3700 Miles to the Pacific Ocean in San Francisco, California. What begins as a search for the true America, during a period of political turmoil, ultimately becomes a story of identity as Gates begins to find clarity and meaning in his own life.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="US Transcontinental"></category><category term="Salomon"></category><category term="The Wandering Fever"></category><category term="Dean Leslie"></category></entry><entry><title>Transcend</title><link href="/transcend.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tad Munnings</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/transcend.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Long-distance running allowed Wesley Korir to escape the grinding poverty of Kenya. But after winning multiple American marathons, including taking...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Long-distance running allowed Wesley Korir to escape the grinding poverty of Kenya. But after winning multiple American marathons, including taking running’s most cherished prize – the Boston Marathon, he risks it all and returns home to help his fellow Kenyans create better lives for themselves. In what proves to be the most challenging race of his career, Wesley takes on a well-financed, big-party candidate to run for a seat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in Kenyan parliament, attempting to balance the frenzy of campaigning with the demands of marathon training. Transcend is the story of the elusive spiritual energy that is somehow forged in the intense rigor of long-distance running, an energy Wesley Korir is using to transform the nation that has done more than any other to change the face of the marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Trials of Miles: Running 650km of the Australian Alps</title><link href="/trials-of-miles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Brett Campbell</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/trials-of-miles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Beau Miles laces up for a different kind of world first, running 650+km of the Australian Alpine Walking Track. Traversing through some of the...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beau Miles laces up for a different kind of world first, running 650+km of the Australian Alpine Walking Track. Traversing through some of the highest peaks in Australia, Beau battles injury, fatigue and ultimately himself in his own personal Trial of Miles. For trail blazers of this new era, running long distance walking trails, passing through wild landscapes quickly seems to nourish a new kind of physical craving. Not, as is the case for Trials of Miles, without questioning how and why we drag ourselves, and our family, into the endevour.  This film unpacks the physical and mindful nature of being the first to run the Australian Alps walking track.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category></entry><entry><title>UltraMarathon Man: 50 Marathons • 50 States • 50 Days</title><link href="/ultra-marathon-man.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>JB Benna</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/ultra-marathon-man.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The inspirational film, UltraMarathon Man: 50 Marathons • 50 States • 50 Days, features renowned endurance athlete and best selling author Dean...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The inspirational film, UltraMarathon Man: 50 Marathons • 50 States • 50 Days, features renowned endurance athlete and best selling author Dean Karnazes in his attempt to run 50 marathons in 50 states in 50 consecutive days to raise awareness for youth obesity and to get America active. A beautiful and epic journey across the United States, during which Dean pushes the limits of human endurance, inspiring thousands across the country to join him along the path while uniting people of all ages and abilities to take “the next step.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="JourneyFilm"></category><category term="JB Benna"></category></entry><entry><title>Ultra-trail du Mont Blanc 2008</title><link href="/ultra-trail-du-mont-blanc-2008.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Denis Lafont</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/ultra-trail-du-mont-blanc-2008.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Reportage sympathique, qui met en valeur l'aventure plutôt que les élites, où l'arriveée de Kilian a lieu au millieu du film, et pas à la fin, car...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reportage sympathique, qui met en valeur l'aventure plutôt que les élites, où l'arriveée de Kilian a lieu au millieu du film, et pas à la fin, car pour tout les autres coureurs n'aventure n'est pas finie. 2008 est l'année où Kilian gagne l'UTMB pour la première fois et devient le plus jeune gagnant de l'histoire de la course.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2005-2009"></category><category term="UTMB"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category></entry><entry><title>Unbreakable</title><link href="/unbreakable.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>JB Benna</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/unbreakable.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Unbreakable: The Western States 100 follows the four lead men on this amazing journey. Hal Koerner, two time defending Western States champion, and...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unbreakable: The Western States 100 follows the four lead men on this amazing journey. Hal Koerner, two time defending Western States champion, and running store entrepreneur from Ashland, Oregon. Geoff Roes, undefeated at the 100-mile distance, an organic chef from Juneau, Alaska. Anton Krupicka, undefeated in every ultramarathon he has ever started, a graduate student living in Boulder, Colorado. Kilian Jornet, the young mountain runner and two time Ultra-trail du Mont-Blanc champion, from Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While their lives may be quite different, the goal is the same: win the Western States 100-mile run. A win will require breaking the course record and running the fastest time in the history of the race. An epic showdown ensues, from Squaw Valley, CA in Lake Tahoe, up though the high snow covered Sierra Nevada Mountains, down through the extreme heat of the American River Canyons and finishing in Auburn, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though all four are undefeated, three must break and only one can remain Unbreakable.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2010-2014"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Anton Krupicka"></category><category term="Kilian Jornet"></category><category term="JourneyFilm"></category><category term="JB Benna"></category></entry><entry><title>Underdog</title><link href="/underdog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Matt Green</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/underdog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I was trying to be like them...UTMB® had become an obsession I felt unable to control at times. It’s not just a 105-mile race in the Alps with...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was trying to be like them...UTMB® had become an obsession I felt unable to control at times. It’s not just a 105-mile race in the Alps with 10,000m of vertical gain. In mountain ultrarunning, it’s the Super Bowl. It usually has the strongest line-up of any trail race in the world, this year including Kilian Jornet, US speedsters Jim Walmsley, Zach Miller and Tim Tollefson'&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="UTMB"></category><category term="Inov-8"></category><category term="Summit Fever Media"></category><category term="Matt Green"></category><category term="Elie Green"></category></entry><entry><title>UTMB: Nuits Blanches</title><link href="/utmb-nuits-blanches.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alexis Berg</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/utmb-nuits-blanches.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;What’s it like to run into the darkness? And not be sure what lies on the other side? We captured the athletes racing the 100-mile Ultra-Trail Mt....&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What’s it like to run into the darkness? And not be sure what lies on the other side?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We captured the athletes racing the 100-mile Ultra-Trail Mt. Blanc through the night, and the human will to chase a dream while fighting to stay awake.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="UTMB"></category><category term="Alexis Berg"></category></entry><entry><title>Where dreams go to die - Gary Robbins and The Barkley Marathons</title><link href="/where-dreams-go-to-die.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ethan Newberry</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/where-dreams-go-to-die.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Where Dreams Go To Die is a documentary created by Ethan Newberry (The Ginger Runner) that follows Canadian ultrarunner, Gary Robbins, during his...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Where Dreams Go To Die is a documentary created by Ethan Newberry (The Ginger Runner) that follows Canadian ultrarunner, Gary Robbins, during his two attempts at completing The Barkley Marathons - a 100+ mile event many consider the toughest endurance run on Earth. Spanning more than 2 years, this journey is emotional, powerful and truly inspirational. Find out what it takes to attempt the impossible and the demons that follow. Learn the sacrifices that come with dedicating one's life to this endeavor. Follow our intimate look at why The Barkley is where dreams go to die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you to all involved in the making of this project. Especially Gary, Linda and Reed for opening their homes and lives to the world during this experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="The Barkley Marathons"></category><category term="Gary Robbins"></category><category term="Ethan Newberry"></category></entry><entry><title>Wildcard: The Story of Western States F7</title><link href="/wildcard-story-of-western-states.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rodolfo Ripado</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/wildcard-story-of-western-states.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Jackie Merritt's epic run at the 2017 Western States 100 Miler&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jackie Merritt's epic run at the 2017 Western States 100 Miler&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category></entry><entry><title>WONDERLAND: Gary Robbins' FKT around Mount Rainier</title><link href="/wonderland.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ethan Newberry</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/wonderland.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;On July 1st, 2015, Gary Robbins - a seasoned and winning ultrarunner - started at Longmire, in the shadow of Mount Rainier, and attempted to set...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On July 1st, 2015, Gary Robbins - a seasoned and winning ultrarunner - started at Longmire, in the shadow of Mount Rainier, and attempted to set the fastest known supported time around the Wonderland Trail. Kyle Skaggs' record of 20 hours 53 minutes was always considered unbeatable. 93 miles, over 24,000ft of elevation gain, and record breaking heat. This day had it all. Could Gary step up to the challenge?&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Gary Robbins"></category><category term="Ethan Newberry"></category></entry><entry><title>Lighting The Fire: Wrong Turns</title><link href="/wrong-turns.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Matt Trappe</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/wrong-turns.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;From 9MindAsylum, &amp;quot;Lighting The Fire: Wrong Turns&amp;quot; tells the story of Jim Walmsley's eventful start in the sport of ultrarunning. After being...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From 9MindAsylum, &amp;quot;Lighting The Fire: Wrong Turns&amp;quot; tells the story of Jim Walmsley's eventful start in the sport of ultrarunning. After being honorably discharged from the Air Force and dealing with bouts of severe depression, Walmsley turned to running to get his life back on track. He moved to Flagstaff, Arizona, and connected with a community of runners who helped him rebound and supported him after his infamous wrong turn at mile 93 of the 2016 Western States 100 race.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2015-x"></category><category term="Western States 100"></category><category term="Jim Walmsley"></category></entry><entry><title>Yannis Kouros - Forever running</title><link href="/yiannis-kouros-forever-running.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Elias Giannakakis</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-31:/yiannis-kouros-forever-running.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Greek film on the ultra-running legend.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Greek film on the ultra-running legend.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="2000-2004"></category></entry></feed>